Guide to the Cedric J. Robinson and Elizabeth P. Robinson Collection on Third World News Review TAM.835
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Third World News Review Episodes, 1981-2015; 1.67 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes and a cassette box; 1.79 Terabytes in 496 computer files; 3 U-matic; 15 VHS; 29 audiocassettes
  - December 2, 2013, TW_TAM_835_ER_412
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Yoel Haile (East Africa). Discussed topics include the geopolitical divisions in Somalia; Maiduguri put on lockdown amid Boko Haram attack in Nigeria; racism in France and France's control of the UN Security Council; parliamentary elections in Mali; and a violent crackdown on undocumented Ethiopian migrant workers in Saudi Arabia.
  - December 9, 2013, TW_TAM_835_ER_413
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Thomas Jacob and Cedric Robinson. Discussed topics include the death of President Nelson Mandela and his legacy; Apartheid; Winnie Mandela and her legacy; Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu avoiding peace talks with Palestine; and the recent elections in India and rise of Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP).
  - December 16, 2013, TW_TAM_835_ER_414
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Ralph Ambruster-Sandoval. Discussed topics include the elections in Honduras and the 2009 Honduran coup d'état; turmoil in Bangui in the Central African Republic and the death of two French soldiers; the elections in Mali; criticisms of the EU's inaction in Syria and lack of assistance for refugees; the transfer of two Saudi prisoners from Guantanamo Bay to Saudi Arabia; and severe floods in Gaza.
  - January 6, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_415
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the South Sudanese Civil War; conflict in Northern Mali; political instability in Burkina Faso; France's interference with the Central African Republic politics and growing violence there; Israel tightening immigration of African refugees; and fighting in Iraq and Syria against al-Qaeda.
  - January 13, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_416
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Katia McClain and Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include the death of Ariel Sharon; the lack of LGBTQ+ rights in Eastern Europe, homophobic laws in Russia, and attempts to ban same-sex marriage in Croatia; the increased number of refugees in Bulgaria; and elections in Chile, the election of Michelle Bachelet as president, and student activist Camila Vallejo being elected to Congress.
  - January 27, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_417
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Jorge Ramirez (Mexico). Discussed topics include homophobia in Africa; the first ceasefire agreement signed during the South Sudanese Civil War; increased xenophobia in France and dissatisfaction with government; fighting in Northern Mali; the Central African Republic elections and election of interim head, Catherine Samba-Panza; and the 2006 teacher's strike in Oaxaca, Mexico.
  - February 10, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_418
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Gary Colmenar and Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include the death of Stuart Hall; the death of Juan Gelman; the economic crisis in Argentina; power supply shortages in Philippines and protests; and the Trans-Pacific Partnership (TPP) and the Trans-Pacific Partnership Agreement (TPPA).
  - February 24, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_419
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Michael Dorsey (Environmental Issues). Discussed topics include the resignation of Egypt's interim government; JStreet versus the American Israel Public Affairs Committee (AIPAC); Michigan electoral districts; international climate justice, injustice movements, and climate crisis in politics; the Islands First initiative; the Green Climate Fund; privatization of climate benefits and energy; and the Chevron oil company in California.
  - March 3, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_421
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Cedric Robinson. Discussed topics include South African platinum mine workers on strike; the South Sudanese Civil War and the violation of a ceasefire agreement; the trial of Pascal Simbikangwa in Paris for his involvement in the Rwandan genocide; the upcoming Algerian presidential election; and President François Hollande's visit to Nigeria and promises to help fight Boko Haram.
  - March 24, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_422
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Gary Colmenar and Ralph Ambruster-Sandoval. Discussed topics include the presidential election in El Salvador; the San Francisco System treaty; disputes over the South Kuril Islands and Liancourt Rocks/Takeshima Islands; the Philippines exploring the possibility of allowing the U.S. and Japan to add more bases; U.S. intervention in Syria and Egypt; and the 2013 Egyptian coup d'etat.
  - March 31, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_423
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the Ebola outbreak in Guinea; South African Public Protector Thuli Madonsela's report about President Jacob Zuma; the Laurent Gbagbo and Charles Blé Goudé trial at the International Criminal Court; violence between Christians and Muslims in the Central African Republic; movement towards seeking justice for missing and murdered indigenous women in Canada; and an investigation of residential school abuses in Canada.
  - circa March 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_420
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Thomas Jacob. Discussed topics include the Syrian Civil War; the Libyan Civil War and Muammar Gaddafi's downfall; the Egyptian crisis; the upcoming elections in India; the trial of Pascal Simbikangwa in Paris for his involvement in the Rwandan genocide; the interim head of Central African Republic Catherine Samba-Panza trying to bring peace to region; and Morocco's King Mohammed VI's visits to African countries.
  - April 14, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_424
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gary Colmenar and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the Truth and Reconciliation Commission of Canada, the history of residential schools, and an investigation into missing and murdered indigenous women in Canada; war crime trials in Libya; the South China Sea dispute; the Enhanced Defense Cooperation Agreement (EDCA) between the U.S. and Philippines; and the Nyanya bombing in Abuja and Boko Haram.
  - April 28, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_425
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Ralph Ambruster-Sandoval and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include Boko Haram, the abduction of 300 girls, and the Nyanya bombing in Abuja, Nigeria; the Movement for Democratic Change (MDC) in Zimbabwe and Morgan Tsvangirai; immigrants' rights hunger strikes across the U.S. and activist Cynthia Diaz; protest over the construction of an ICE detention center in Santa Maria, CA; and the collapse of Israel-Palestine peace talks.
  - May 12, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_426
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Ralph Ambruster-Sandoval and Jovian Radheshwar (South Asia). Discussed topics include Boko Haram and abduction of 300 girls in Nigeria; the abuse of political and military power in Nigeria; the forced removal of the attorney general of Guatemala Claudia Paz y Paz; human rights violations in Guatemala; and the growing number of polio cases in Pakistan.
  - May 19, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_427
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Thomas Jacob. Discussed topics include the Indian elections and overwhelming popularity of the Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP); the looming drought in Syria and its impact on the refugee crisis; and President Goodluck Jonathan's mishandling of the abduction of school girls by Boko Haram.
  - June 2, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_429
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Jorge Ramirez (Mexico) and Gary Colmenar. Discussed topics include Boko Haram and abduction of 300 girls in Nigeria; the increased number of sexual violence cases against women in the Democratic Republic of the Congo and the South Sudan; the South China Sea dispute; the Nobel Peace Prize and Article 9 of the Japanese Constitution; the death of Yuri Kochiyama; and the Zapatistas in Chiapas, Mexico and the death of Subcomandante Marcos.
  - June 16, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_430
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Ralph Ambruster-Sandoval and Gary Colmenar. Discussed topics include the collapse of the Maliki government in Iraq; the Islamic State of Iraq and al-Sham (ISIS); the Central American immigration crisis and the ill treatment of refugees in American detention centers; the significant increase in child migrants from Central America; and protests in the Philippines against government corruption.
  - June 30, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_431
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Thomas Jacob. Discussed topics include the bodies of three missing Israeli teenagers found in the West Bank; the Sykes–Picot Agreement; the Israeli police re-arresting 1,000 African asylum seekers; the ISIS-Kurdish War; the Jinnah International Airport attack; the increase in honor killings in Pakistan and increase in traditional Islamic values; and the Hindu Mission Army and the increase in right wing Hindu nationalism in India.
  - circa June 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_428
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include Argentina's international debt crisis; the World Cup in Brazil and demonstrations against excessive public spending for the event; the re-election of President Mohamed Ould Abdel Aziz in Mauritania; the upcoming trial of Karim Wade in Senegal; the upcoming trial of President Hissène Habré in Senegal; and political instability in Mali and fighting in Northern Mali.
  - July 7, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_432
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Katia McClain and Yoel Haile (East Africa). Discussed topics include the South Stream pipeline; major floods in the Balkans; violent mass evictions of impoverished people living in informal settlements in South Africa; and the Economic Freedom Fighters (EFF).
  - July 14, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_433
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include the US signing a $11 billion arms deal with Qatar; a global meeting in Vienna to discuss Iranian nuclear capabilities; the Gaza War and Operation Protective Edge; the kidnapping of 300 schools girls in Nigeria by Boko Haram; the death of Nadine Gordimer; and France inviting heads of African nations to centennial celebrations of World War I in France and recognizing African contributions to the war.
  - July 21, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_434
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Katia McClain. Discussed topics include the crash of Malaysia Airlines Flight 17 in Eastern Ukraine; the civil war in Eastern Ukraine; the Gaza War; an increase of child migrants from Central America entering the US and being held under terrible conditions in detention centers; and growing protests against deportations from the U.S.
  - July 28, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_435
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Gary Colmenar. Discussed topics include the Ebola outbreak in Africa; Boko Haram and the 300 kidnapped Nigerian girls; the South African union of metal workers ending their one month strike; France and the U.S. sending assistance to Africa to fight Boko Haram; talks for a peace treaty in Northern Mali to end hostilities; the Central African Republic peace treaty with Seleka rebels in Brazzaville; and the State of the Nation Address of Philippines President Benigno Simeon Aquino III.
  - August 4, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_436
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Katia McClain. Discussed topics include the Ebola outbreak in Africa; the Gaza War and a pro-Gaza protest in Tel Aviv; the civil war in Ukraine; the inability to collect remains of Malaysia Airlines Flight 17, which was allegedly shot down by Russian separatist forces; and major bank runs in Bulgaria after the collapse of Bulgaria's CorpBank.
  - August 11, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_437
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include the Israeli attack against the southern Gaza town of Khuza; Human Rights Watch condemning Israel and Palestine for war atrocities against civilians; the conflict in Gaza being linked to anti-semitic attacks in France; thousands marching for Gaza in Cape Town; the U.S.-Africa Leaders Summit; and the Ebola epidemic in Africa.
  - August 18, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_438
    The moderator of the episode was Katia McClain and the guests were Hector Javkin and Thomas Jacob. Discussed topics include ISIS; Pakistan's Imran Khan and Tahirul Qadri at the Islamabad rally; the Indian general election, the Bharatiya Janata Party's (BJP) victory, the election of Narendra Modi as prime minister, and the rise of Indian right-wing Hindu nationalism; the civil war in Ukraine; the investigation of war crimes by the Kosovo Liberation Army; and the history of children stolen and illegally adopted during the 1976–1983 Argentine military dictatorship and Estela de Carlotto locating her long-lost grandson via a DNA bank.
  - August 25, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_439
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include Boko Haram; the growing number of journalists killed in Israel and attempts to try to suppress truth about Gaza; the Ebola crisis in Africa frightening France; President François Hollande joining African leaders in honoring Operation Dragoon from World War II; the Ebola outbreak in the Democratic Republic of the Congo; the International Criminal Court considering charges against Israel for war atrocities in Palestine; and Palestinians and Ferguson, MO protesters uniting virtually.
  - September 8, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_440
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Gary Colmenar. Discussed topics include a scandal involving South African President Cyril Ramaphosa and game farms; child labor in the Philippines; Kosal Khiev and a documentary about him called Cambodian Son; the South China Sea dispute; the Iraqi parliament approving a new government and Haider al-Abadi as new prime minister; ISIS; and the ongoing conflict in Gaza.
  - September 15, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_441
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Thomas Jacob. Discussed topics include a global alliance against the Islamic State (ISIS) and Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL); President Barack Obama and war contractors; Denmark introducing rehab programs for Syrian fighters; Egyptian hunger striker Alaa Abdel-Fattah's release; Israeli Defense Force Refuseniks facing backlash from the Israeli military and government; the origins of ISIS and ISIL; elections in Afghanistan; and a major flood in the Kashmir Valley.
  - September 22, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_442
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guest was Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the People's Climate March; Cuba sending medical professionals to West Africa to help with the Ebola outbreak; the Ebola outbreak and lockdown in Sierra Leone; journalists killed while covering the Ebola education campaign in Guinea; and fighting in Syria against ISIS.
  - September 29, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_443
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include unrest in Argentina due to the debt crisis and Paul Singer; controversy surrounding César Milani, military Chief of Staff of Argentina; the República de los Niños (The Children's Republic) in Argentina; the film Flying Paper; the Khorasan group; and the Houthi takeover in Yemen.
  - October 6, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_444
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Gary Colmenar. Discussed topics include President Uhuru Kenyatta indicted by the International Criminal Court and his resignation; the death of former Haitian President Jean-Claude "Baby Doc" Duvalier; scandals surrounding President Jacob Zuma of South Africa; Mali's ancient manuscripts being smuggled to safety from Timbuktu; Japan whitewashing World War II history; a bill proposed in the Philippines to provide reparations to victims of Martial Law; and Sweden recognizing Palestine as a state.
  - October 14, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_445
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include growing protests in Israel against the high court ruling declaring internment camps of African refugees as unconstitutional; the Hannibal Directive and the Israeli Defense Forces; the potential for Israel to be tried for war crimes related to their attack on Rafah; Malala Yousafzai winning the Nobel Peace Prize; the re-election of Evo Morales as president of Bolivia; a movement to close the School of Americas; protests from Argentina's Mapuche indigenous peoples to stop fracking in their region; protests relating to the Iguala mass kidnapping; and the death of Ali Mazrui.
  - October 27, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_446
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Maryam Griffin (Palestine) and Cedric Robinsonn. Discussed topics include the Rwandan government banning the BBC from broadcasting in their country; the 20th anniversary of Rwandan genocide and a controversial BBC documentary about the genocide; Boko Haram; instability in South Sudan; Maryam Griffin's dissertation on the politics of transportation in the West Bank; Palestinian Freedom riders; and Israeli Defense Minister Moshe Ya'alon's attempts to prevent Palestinians with work permits from accessing the West Bank via Israeli buses.
  - November 10, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_447
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include the film On The Side of the Road; the ongoing conflict between Israel and Palestine; the Iraq War and body counts; World War I history; and the Burkina Faso uprising and history of Burkina Faso.
  - November 24, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_448
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Thomas Jacob and Gary Colmenar. Discussed topics include President Barack Obama's executive order that would limit deportations of undocumented peoples; immigration reform and policies globally; a suicide bomber killing 45 at an Afghanistan volleyball game; the Pakistani Taliban; blasphemy laws in Pakistan and India; an upsurge in Hindu nationalism ushered in by Prime Minister Narendra Modi's government; the fifth anniversary of the Ampatuan massacre in Philippines; and indigenous people from the Palawan Island in the Philippines protesting against plans to mine nickel on their land.
  - December 1, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_449
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Ralph Ambruster-Sandoval. Discussed topics include the Cairo Criminal Court dropping murder and corruption charges against President Hosni Mubarak; Syrian refugees; the Iguala mass kidnapping and protests against President Enrique Peña Nieto of Mexico; the Nigerian parliament planning to give President Goodluck Jonathan a bill of impeachment; and Boko Haram.
  - December 15, 2014, TW_TAM_835_ER_450
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include a Senate Intelligence Committee report examining the CIA's use of torture; the use of torture in Argentina; Guantanamo Bay and Abu Ghraib Prison; and the use of torture globally as an interrogation tactic.
  - January 12, 2015, TW_TAM_835_ER_451
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Jovian Radheshwar (South Asia). Discussed topics include Boko Haram; political, military, and civil instability in Nigeria; the Paris Unity March; re-established political relations between the U.S. and Cuba; the history of American embargoes on Cuba; and the Rojava (Autonomous Administration of North and East Syria, AANES) and ISIS.
  - January 15, 2015, TW_TAM_835_ER_452
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include the ongoing conflict between Israel and Palestine; the Iraq War and body counts; Boko Haram and military efforts in Nigeria to combat them; destabilization in Sub-Saharan Western Africa; and Ezadeen and migrant ghost ships.
  - January 26, 2015, TW_TAM_835_ER_453
    The moderator of the episode was Hector Javkin and the guests were Ralph Ambruster-Sandoval and Gary Colmenar. Discussed topics include the death of Argentinian lawyer Alberto Nisman; Pedro Garcia Arredondo being found guilty of killing 37 activists in Guatemala and Guatemalan politics; and Pope Francis' visit to the Philippines and Filipino politics.
  - February 2, 2015, TW_TAM_835_ER_454
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include fighting in Kobanî, Turkey against ISIL and ISIS; Kurdish women in Syria being granted equal rights in defiance of ISIS; Australian Al-Jazeera journalist Peter Greste being released from an Egyptian jail; the Charlie Hebdo shooting in Paris and the growing threat against freedom of press in France; growing racism in France; Boko Haram; and a car bombing in Nigeria after President Goodluck Jonathan's rally.
  - February 9, 2015, TW_TAM_835_ER_455
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Thomas Jacob and Cedric Robinson. Discussed topics included the death of Assia Djebar; Nigeria postponing the presidential vote for security reasons; Boko Haram; President Robert Mugabe becoming Chairperson of the African Union; stability in India with Narendra Modi as prime minister with continued issues; racial tensions in India and the growing power of Hindu Mahasabha; and incidents of churches burning in Delhi.
  - February 23, 2015, TW_TAM_835_ER_456
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include ISIS; Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's visit to the U.S. to meet with Congress, but not President Barack Obama; Egyptian activist and blogger Abd El-Fattah being sent to prison; and the increased migration from African refugees into Europe and the fear of radical Islamists and terrorism.
  - March 9, 2015, TW_TAM_835_ER_457